myflowertree.com 2014-11-16

# Privacy Policy

**www.myflowertree.com** recognizes and respects the importance of maintaining the privacy of our customers, registered members ("Members") and users, and has established this Privacy Policy as a result. The purpose of this Privacy Policy is to inform you of:

  * the personal information we may collect from you when you visit our Web Site, respond to our emails, place orders via mail or fax, use our mobile applications, place orders through social media applications (such as our Facebook App) or otherwise contact us via telephone, email, fax or mail (collectively, our "Services"),
  * why we gather information from you,
  * how we collect it,
  * how we use it, and
  * the choices you have regarding our use of personal information you have provided.

This Privacy Policy is part of the Terms of Use, which governs your use of our Web Site located at **www.myflowertree.com** or the "Web Site".This Privacy Policy does not cover information provided to our Company-owned or franchised retail stores.

Note: You must be 18 years or older and the age of majority in your place of residence to use, subscribe or register as a member of www.myflowertree.com (or 21 years or older in the event that you place a request for transmission of an order for a product containing alcohol). The Service is a general audience site and we do not knowingly collect, maintain or disclose personal information from or about children under 13 years of age.

 **Mode and place of processing the Data**

 **Method of processing**

The Data Controller processes the Data of Users in proper manner and shall take appropriate security measures to prevent unauthorized access, disclosure, modification or unauthorized destruction of the Data.

Access to the Data may be available to Data Processors, if appointed, as well as employees involved with the processing. Access to Data may be also available to external parties providing services to the Data Controller such as third party technical service providers, mail carriers, hosting providers, IT companies, communication agencies. The updated list of these parties may be requested from the Data Controller at any time.

 **Place**

The Data is processed at the Data Controller headquarters, unless stated otherwise in the rest of this document.

 **Conservation Time**

The Data is kept for the time necessary to provide the service requested by the User, or stated by the purposes outlined in this document, and the User can always request the Data Controller for their suspension or removal.

 **Why do we gather information?**

www.myflowertree.com gathers personal information to help improve our products and customer service, to communicate with you, to process your orders, to provide an enhanced and more personalized shopping experience and to inform you, and your gift and message recipients, of special offers and discounts from us, our affiliated brands and selected third parties.

 **What information do we gather?**

We collect information through our Web Site, emails, mail, fax, telephone, mobile applications and social media applications (such as our Facebook App) including when you:

• place an order,

• participate in our forums, surveys, contests, sweepstakes, promotions, content submissions, chats, bulletin boards, discussion groups, requests for suggestions, and membership registrations, and

• engage in other activities, services, products and resources we make accessible to our customers, members or users.

Depending on how you are interact with us, we collect some or all of the following types of information:

• your name, address, telephone number, email address,

• billing information (credit/debit card number, expiration date, alternate or additional billing information and billing address),

• gender and birth date, if you choose, or are otherwise required to, enter such information,

• products purchased and occasion type (for example, Mother's Day),

• any promotion or gift card code and related information (for example, if you are claiming frequent flyer miles),

• Message and gift recipients' names, addresses, telephone numbers and email addresses, and

• other information you provide to us, including User Submissions (defined in the Terms of Use).

Information you provide to us may be collected by us even if an order, registration, or other process is started but not completed or otherwise cancelled. Members may also add to their Address Book the name, address and telephone number of friends or other persons to whom they may wish to send gifts or expressions. Other Members do not have the right to view and edit your Address Book entries.

 **How we use "Cookies" and "Action Tags".**

A "cookie" is a small data file sent to your browser from a web server and stored on your computer. We use cookies to let us know that you are a prior customer, user or Member and to provide certain features to you. Most web browsers allow you to instruct the browser to prevent the use of cookies. However, if you disable this feature, certain aspects of the Services, such as the shopping basket, may not function properly.

We have relationships with third parties who may receive non-personal information directly from the cookies placed by our Services on your computer to assist in analyzing our business and customers.

Our Services may also use a common web technology "called "action tags" (also called single pixel gifs or web beacons) to anonymously track purchase, usage and other web activity information. Action tags may be used to provide data to third parties for tracking purposes. However, our Services do not use action tags to collect or transfer personal information. In addition, third parties may set their own cookies and tags through our Services (such as through interest-based advertising, described below). We do not control such third parties or their privacy practices. If you do not want third parties to be able to use such methods, you should modify your browser settings to limit such access.

 **How we use the information we collect**

We use information we collect to communicate with you, to process your orders, to provide an enhanced and more personalized shopping experience, to inform you and your gift and message recipients of offers and discounts from www.myflowertree.com and our affiliated brands and to enable you to receive credits for purchases under loyalty or buying programs which you have joined. In addition, we may make such information (except for credit/debit card number and expiration date, unless you consent otherwise), including aggregated information, available to selected third parties including, but not limited to, those who share or rent information for direct marketing purposes.

However, without your consent, we do not make your, or your gift or message recipients' email addresses, available to "third parties" (as that term is defined and limited below). For example, we may make your postal address available to third parties for marketing purposes, however we would not share your email address without your consent. In addition, you may instruct that other personal information about you or your message or gift recipients' that you have provided to us not be shared with third parties by following the instructions in How to Limit the Use of Personal Information, below.

Our Affiliates, subcontractors, and agents, and any successors or assignees to our business (if we ever sell, lease, license or assign some or all of our business), are not considered to be third parties under this Policy. We may provide your information to our Affiliates for use in connection with their businesses, including sending you offers and promotions. However, in connection with information collected under this Policy, they are required to comply with this Policy. "Affiliates" are persons or entities directly or indirectly controlling, controlled by, or under common control with, or in the same corporate family as, www.myflowertree.com, Inc.

We may combine information we receive from you via our Services with information from our Affiliates and third parties. We use the combined information to enhance and personalize your shopping experience with us and to communicate with you in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

We reserve the right to disclose information you provide to us as required by law, in response to legal process and law enforcement requests and as necessary or appropriate, in our view, to operate the Services, process orders or registrations, to conduct promotions, contests, and sweepstakes you participate in, and to protect the rights or property of the Company, its Affiliates, users, customers, recipients, Members, Sponsors, Providers, Licensors, Merchants and Associates (as these terms are defined in the Terms of Use).

 **Please note that any personal information you reveal or post on one our public forums (as defined in the Terms of Use), such as a message board, chat room, discussion group, folder, survey, contest, sweepstakes, user review and rate forum, and all User Submissions, are not protected by this Privacy Policy and may be collected, shared and used by us and with third parties, including to contact you. Information you give out or post on our public forums you disclose at your own risk.**

 **Consent to Transfer and Submission**

Our Services are operated in the United States. If you are located outside the United States, please be aware that any information you provide to us will be transferred to and stored in the United States. By using the Services or otherwise providing us with information, you hereby consent to this transfer.

Although personal information collected by us through the our Services will be used by us in accordance with this Privacy Policy, laws generally applicable to the protection of personal data in the U.S. may not be as stringent as those in other countries.

 **Links to Other Web Sites**

www.myflowertree.com wants you to be aware that when you click on links and/or ad banners that take you to affiliated or third-party services, you will be subject to the privacy policies and terms of use of those services, not ours. We encourage you to read the posted privacy statement and user terms whenever using, and prior to providing any personal information to, any other service.

 **Security and Passwords**

If you place an order on our Web site, it encrypts the credit/debit card number you submit prior to transmission over the Internet using secure socket layer (SSL) encryption technology. This technology works best when the Web Site is viewed using Microsoft IE®, Google Chrome®, Mozilla Firefox®, and Apple Safari® browsers. However, no transmission of data over the Internet or any other network can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. Although we make reasonable efforts to safeguard personal information once we receive it, we cannot warrant the security of information we receive.

Portions of the Services (such as our Member registration and Address Book) may require registration and log-in processes in which you will select a user ID and password (collectively, the "Password"). Passwords provided to you by us are the confidential property of the Company and may be used by you solely for your individual use of the Services (and otherwise as specified by us). You are responsible for maintaining the confidentiality of any Password and for all activities that occur using your Password, whether or not authorized by you. You agree to immediately notify us of any unauthorized use of your Password or accounts.

We may provide you with the ability to log into our Services using a social media account, such as Facebook Connect. We do not control the activities of such social media services and have no control over the data they collect or their privacy practices. You should review their privacy practices before using any such social media service.

 **How to Limit the Use of Personal Information**

We want to communicate with you only to the extent you want to hear from us. If you prefer not to have personal information collected from you via the Services shared with third parties, or to set your preferences concerning promotional communications, please follow the directions below.

 **From Third Parties**

We do not share email addresses you provide with third parties without your consent. In addition, if you prefer that other personal information provided by you not be shared with third parties, please let us know by emailing, writing or calling us as described below and identify the personal information that you would prefer not to be shared. Your instructions will be processed as soon as reasonably practicable and in accordance with law.

 **Additional information about Data collection and processing**

 **Legal Action**

The User's Personal Data may be used for legal purposes by the Data Controller, in Court or in the stages leading to possible legal action arising from improper use of this Application or the related services.

 **Additional Information about User's Personal Data**

In addition to the information in this privacy policy, this Application may provide the User with contextual information concerning particular services or the collection and processing of Personal Data.

 **System Logs and Maintenance**

For operation and maintenance purposes, this Application and any third party services may collect files that record interaction with this Application (System Logs) or use for this purpose other Personal Data (such as IP Address).

 **Information not contained in this policy**

More details concerning the collection or processing of Personal Data may be requested from the Data Controller at any time at its contact information.

 **The rights of Users**

Users have the right, at any time, to know whether their Personal Data has been stored and can consult the Data Controller to learn about their contents and origin, to verify their accuracy or to ask for them to be supplemented, cancelled, updated or corrected, or for their transformation into anonymous format or to block any data held in violation of the law, as well as to oppose their treatment for any and all legitimate reasons. Requests should be sent to the Data Controller at the contact information set out above.

 **Changes to this privacy policy**

The Data Controller reserves the right to make changes to this privacy policy at any time by giving notice to its Users on this page. It is strongly recommended to check this page often, referring to the date of the last modification listed at the bottom. If a User objects to any of the changes to the Policy, the User must cease using this Application and can request the Data Controller to erase the Personal Data. Unless stated otherwise, the then-current privacy policy applies to all Personal Data the Data Controller has about Users.

 **Information about this privacy policy**

The Data Controller is responsible for this privacy policy.

Emailing us at: **support@MyFlowerTree.com** from the email address which you wish to have removed (i.e. not shared with third parties), and include your postal mailing address in the message; or

Writing us at:  
 **Customer Support Department**  
 **www.myflowertree.com, INC.**

Telephoning us at (+91 98711 41000)

(Please, include or tell us your mailing address, and if you have a catalog, brochure or other mailing label from us, please include it with your request or have it ready when you call).
